<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://willijeong1.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://willijeong1.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-05-25T08:33:17+00:00</updated><id>https://willijeong1.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><entry><title type="html">MOCA, a cappella for everyone</title><link href="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2024/moca-acappella/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MOCA, a cappella for everyone"/><published>2024-10-06T22:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-06T22:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2024/moca-acappella</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2024/moca-acappella/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/moca_00-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/moca_00-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/moca_00-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/moca_00.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> MOCA, a cappella for everyone. </div> <p>MOCA is an acronym of “modu-ui (모두의; of everyone) acappella,” which I think is already an ample explanation of what we do in this club. MOCA is an amateur a cappella club where medical students in Seoul National University get together to host annual shows of “voice magic” open to the school and hospital community as well as visitors. For me, MOCA is a grateful opportunity to ventilate and relax, away from my medical studies and research.</p> <p>As a member, I sang in a number of performances, mainly as a tenor. Below are a list of videos that I appear in. I hope some songs sound familiar!</p> <p>I also belong to the musical coordination team, where we manage our extensive reservoir of a cappella scores and compose or transcribe cool songs we encounter on the internet (or help a member do so). Most importantly, we select songs for the annual show program and assign members to each song, considering various aspects such as vocal range and color, the character of each performance, voice blending, and so on. I have made and shared quite a few a cappella arrangements myself; I look forward to putting some of those on stage eventually.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K13rA4NQZ10" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eARFdEC5D2I" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> My performances in the 8th annual concert in October 2022. (left) "when the party's over" by Billie Eilish (arr. Pentatonix). I'm very sure those of you reading this post know this song. (right) "A Sailor's Lament" by The Idea of North. Boy, this was hard to practice! </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Iy6p_UT3zOw" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> My performance in the 9th annual concert in October 2023. "Snow" by Rajaton. This one was my first song as a team leader. Can you feel the subtle sounds of snow falling outside the window? </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DBFGueQXVgI" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OCRs5b3J1qw" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> My performances in the 10th annual concert in October 2024. (left) "Ebb Tide" by The Righteous Brothers (arr. Fred King). Our very first and successful attempt at a barbershop quartet! (right) "Butterfly" by Rajaton. This song has a weird ethnic (?) vibe and we all loved it. </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="a-cappella"/><category term="musical-performance"/><category term="community"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Singing together through medical school at Seoul National University]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reaching out firsthand： Precise prevention of adolescent suicide in South Korea</title><link href="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2022/suicidal-ideation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reaching out firsthand： Precise prevention of adolescent suicide in South Korea"/><published>2022-12-14T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-14T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2022/suicidal-ideation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2022/suicidal-ideation/"><![CDATA[<p>*** This project was for a term paper in the “Data Science in Human Neuroimaging” course in Fall 2022, led by Dr. Jiook Cha (Department of Psychology, Seoul National University). I worked with two other students majoring in Psychology to devise and analyze the prediction model.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_00-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_00-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_00-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_00.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Reaching out firsthand. </div> <p>*** An intriguing finding from this project was that behavioral assessment data showed a striking adeptness, compared to gene and brain imaging data, in generally predicting suicidal ideation. In retrospect, I believe this is an example describing the robust clinical efficacy of the current symptom-based diagnosis and treatment framework for psychiatric disorders. However, at the same time, it implies that the complex disparity between biological correlates and behavioral manifestations of mental illness, a major unsolved question in psychiatry research, would be nearly impossible to address without refining (or possibly revising) our current conceptualization of psychiatric disorders.</p> <p>*** Revisiting this originally Korean post in 2024 to translate it for potential international visitors, I again feel heartbroken looking at the still rising adolescent suicide rates in my country. Even the mere thinking of the unfathomable struggles these young people would have went through before deciding to voluntarily end their own life makes me shudder. The most frightening and frustrating part about this is that I, currently living in a society that puts excessive burden on the people but remains to deem mental illness as strictly taboo, can too understand in part why these thousands of already lost souls might have thought of suicide as the last and only option left. Life should not be this way for young South Koreans, or any other person in Korea, or the world for that matter. We need to do something, anything. NOW.</p> <hr/> <p>Adolescent suicide has long become a serious societal problem in South Korea. The country is now routinely scoring a disgraceful “first place” in age-adjusted suicide rates in OECD member countries. Suicide takes up the highest proportion in causes of South Korean adolescent death, and this number keeps increasing, leading to a paradoxical rise in suicide despite the decrease in total mortality. In 2021, an average 36.6 people per day committed suicide; that is one person per every 39 minutes. It is downright shocking that, if one lived in a hypothetical apartment complex housing about 4,000 residents, this number would be akin to one neighbor, friend, or family member per year. Moreover, as if this is not devastating enough, the recent lack of social relationship due to COVID-19 has only aggravated suicide rates.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-8 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_01_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_01_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_01_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_01_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_02_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_02_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_02_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_02_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_03_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_03_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_03_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_03_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Adolescent suicide has long become a serious societal problem in South Korea. </div> <p>Various attempts have gone underway in South Korea to lower this devastating suicide rate, which does not even seem to budge. For instance, in the capital Seoul, signposts with supportive messages were attached to particular “suicide bridges” on the Hangang River,* and phone booths were installed to connect attempters with suicide helpline service. Another preventive strategy came in the form of educational programs such as the “Watch-Listen-Talk Strategy” and the “Lifesaving Gatekeeper Program,” where teenagers and young adults are regularly coached to sense and provide assistance to high-risk peers around them. While these efforts are agreed upon to have valid social impacts in themselves, they are not sufficient in reversing the steep incline of adolescent suicide that continues on. To overthrow this tendency, it is necessary to devise a more direct and precise intervention strategy, considering the characteristics of adolescents that “fall through the safety net.”</p> <p>*Note: The Hangang River flows through the center of the Seoul metropolitan area with over 25 bridges across the 1km-wide (about 0.6 mi) waters. Although the riverbank is well-known for its refreshing scenery and is a perfect picnic spot for many Seoulites, a few bridges across the river are unfortunately recognized as popular “suicide spots” to some.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_04_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_04_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_04_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_04_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_05_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_05_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_05_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_05_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_06_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_06_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_06_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_06_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_07_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_07_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_07_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_07_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Examples of current attempts to lower adolescent suicide rates in South Korea. </div> <p>A notable reason behind the insufficiency of suicide prevention policies in saving lives comes from South Korea’s cultural norms regarding the perception of illness. Koreans habitually tend to hide their weaknesses and digress from their true feelings when they speak, which impedes opportunities for early intervention against many health problems. Espceially in terms of mood disorders - anxiety and depression problems are widespread amid the socioeconomic struggles the country faces - that seldom manifest explicitly, the Korean society often stigmatizes mental health problems and rather attributes them to incompetency or lack of integrity. Since mental illness is strictly considered as taboo in both personal and societal aspects, many patients acknowledge their condition too late and arrive at the clinic in much advanced crises, let alone benefit from early detection.</p> <p>The steep incline of adolescent suicide in spite of clinically significant preventive measures seems to indicate that an unexpectedly high number of teens and young adults cover up their ideations of suicide and evade timely intervention. Considering the aforementioned cultural indifference to mental illness, preventive educational programs addressing the whole peer group might have proven otherwise for high-risk individuals in South Korea. To elaborate, if these teens and young adults thinking of suicide were led to think that it is “embarrassing” to admit their suffering, these anti-suicide sessions would only have heightened their self pressure in the effort to “fit in” with the others. Furthermore, even if the preventive programs were effective, it is questionnable whether high-risk adolescents had an understanding household environment where they would have had a chance to speak up about their problems. Concerning results from a nationwide survey indeed demonstrated that family members, with whom many teens spent most of their time with before ending their own lives, failed to recognize the warning signals these helpless youth repeatedly sent out.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_08-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_08-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_08-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_08.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-8 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_09_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_09_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_09_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_09_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A number of teens and young adults may cover up suicidal ideations to "fit in," evading timely intervention. </div> <p>An idealistic solution to the South Korean suicide crisis would be to promote social norm changes to allow individuals to acknowledge and seek help for their mental health problems, naturally resulting in adolescents with suicidal ideation receiving assistance as they need. Although this scenario does not seem impossible since younger generations in South Korea are becoming more vigilant towards mental health and well-being, the already devastating suicide rate that keeps rising rapidly by the minute calls for a more immediate approach. Taking into account the societal and cultural insensitivity towards suicidal ideation, the safety net against suicide could be widened by screening “silent” high-risk teens and young adults to intervene adequately. With this rationale, prediction models based on a combination of indirect variables, e.g. questionnaires and biological risk scores, could effectively detect the subtle nonverbal signals pointing to suicide. An investigation to compare and select such appropriate variables would thus provide valuable insights into early detection and prevention of adolescent suicide in South Korea.</p> <hr/> <p>To evaluate suicide risk of suicide in adolescents, a good starting point is the differences between children with or without suicidal ideation. For this exemplary investigation, we included demographic information, polygenic risk scores (PRS), brain morphometry, functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) and white matter diffusion MRI (dMRI) data, and child behavior checklist (CBCL) scores.</p> <p>PRS represents genetic susceptibility to sucidal ideation that one is born with; this susceptibility, however, does not by itself lead directly to suicidal ideation. Inherited genotypes manifest as behavioral characteristics with influence from various environmental variables, and the brain acts as the mediator in the interactions between gene and environment. We employed brain morphometry (regional thickness and curvature) and dMRI data (connectivity in axon-rich white matter) to represent this mediator role. The fMRI data consists of regional activity levels during a “go-no-go” task, which represents the degree of impulse control in making a quick decision to or not to press a button following a given signal.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-3 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_10-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_10-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_10-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_10.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-3 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The brain as the mediator of gene-environmental interactions to determine behavioral characteristics. </div> <p>Environmental factors have major influences in the connection from genetic susceptibility to actual intent and commitment of suicide. Unfortunately, a comprehensive index representing infinitely diverse and individual lifestyles is yet to be established, hence we included some basic demographic information such as education level, marital status, and household income. We assumed that scores on the CBCL questionnaire, an intimate behavioral assessment filled out by caregivers, would complement the limitations of demographic data by accounting for environmental influences as incorporated into the child’s observable behavior.</p> <p>Based on the above information, we performed automated machine learning (autoML) with the h2o package on R, a statistical computing software environment, to devise an effective screening model for children with high risk of suicide. Data for each variable was obtained from the ABCD (Adolescent Brain Cognitive Development) Study® on children 9–11 years of age in the United States.* The screening model was trained to predict whether a participant has suicidal ideation (dependent variable) from the indirect variables mentioned above (independent variables). We analyzed 1750 participants who reported suicidal ideation (experimental group) alongside participants without health problems (control group). Independent variables with excessive blank values or zero variance were removed to omit unintended bias in classification, and continuous variables were scaled to means of 0 and standard deviations of 1. For CBCL variables, raw scores (not T-scores) were scaled to allow for integrative analyses with variables from other modalities.</p> <p>We randomly assigned data for 525 participants (30% of total) to test the efficacy of models; the prediction model was trained on the remaining 1225 participants. This separation of training and testing data ensures high reliability in autoML results. To address overfitting issues where the devised model’s prediction criteria adheres specifically to the training dataset and would not be effective to other, real-life datasets, we also randomly organized the training data of 1225 participants into 5 different folds. The autoML process automatically selected and optimized a combination of machine learning algorithms, e.g. generalized linear model (GLM), gradient boosting machine (GBM), deep learning, distributed random forest (DRF), and ensemble learning, to best predict suicidal ideation.</p> <p>The efficacy of prediction models were compared according to sensitivity and specificity as well as the area under the curve (AUC). To elaborate, sensitivity refers to the proportion of participants with suicidal ideation, which the model successfully predicts the presence of. Specificity refers to the proportion of participants without suicidal ideation, i.e. healthy participants, who are predicted not to have suicidal thoughts. The AUC is calculated from the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve, which depicts sensitivity against a given value of false positive rate (the proportion of healthy participants erroneously predicted of having thought of suicide) at each threshold setting.</p> <p>*Note: Since there were no extensive datasets available for South Korean youth, we accessed the ABCD Study® for a general analysis including various ethnic and cultural backgrounds. By doing this, we also anticipated that the results could not only be applied to Korea, but also similar suicide intervention studies around the world. We strongly assert that establishing a South Korean youth database would immensely assist in national efforts against adolescent suicide.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-7 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_11-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_11-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_11-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_11.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-5 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_12_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_12_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_12_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_12_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> (left) Demonstration of the ABCD Study® framework. (right) Outline of autoML for suicide prediction. </div> <p>Before training the initial model including all independent variables, we evaluated the predictability of each variable using a univariate GLM. We proceeded on to autoML on selected variables which showed significant predictability in simple linear regression (p &lt; .05). The trained prediction model predicted the dependent variable (suicidal ideation) in a satisfactory manner (AUC = 0.950, sensitivity = 0.816, specificity = 0.990). It was notable that almost all CBCL variables passed the variable selection by solitary predictability and also expressed highly dominant explainability in the initial prediction model. The below right figure depicts that the top 11 variables with highest explainability were all from CBCL.</p> <p>Meanwhile, contrary to common belief, brain imaging data failed to show meaningful predictability even from the variable selection process. Among brain morphometry, fMRI, and dMRI variables, only 2.57%, 0.29%, and 5.60% respectively were classified as significant. Though some dMRI variables could be distinguished for having moderate predictability, CBCL variables dominated all of these distinct variables by explainability. It is worth mentioning that distinguished dMRI variables pointed to the connectivity between left amygdala and left nucleus accumbens or left lateral orbitofrontal cortex, along with the connectivity between left insula and right middle temporal gyrus. These connections have been reported to constitute circuits related to anxiety, depression, or the reward system. Moreover, fMRI measurement of activity in the left nucleus accumbens also showed significant predictibility alone. Overall, we anticipated that predictability of these variables from brain imaging data would improve when their interactions with PRS - PRS variables had negligible explainability - were included.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-8 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_13-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_13-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_13-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_13.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-3 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_14_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_14_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_14_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_14_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-3 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> (left) Explainability for top 20 independent variables in the initial autoML model including all variables. (right) Proportion of selected brain imaging data variables with significant predictability in the univariate GLM (p &lt; .05). GM, WM connectivity, and Task fMRI respectively refer to brain morphometry, dMRI, and fMRI data. </div> <p>The striking predictability of CBCL scores on suicidal ideation was robustly reproduced in a different prediction model that included demographic and CBCL variables only (AUC = 0.966, sensitivity = 0.801, specificity = 0.990). Among the CBCL variables, high explainability was attributed to the “broadband” Total Problems score, encompassing internalizing or externalizing problems, alongside the “narrowband” Anxious/Depressed scale. Indeed, incorporated in these assessments are factors reported to be significantly related to suicidal ideation, e.g. dysfunctional behavior, anxiety and depression, and impulsivity.</p> <p>This led to a new research question: would requesting caregivers to fill out CBCL questionnaires be solely sufficient in precisely and effectively predicting and intervening with suicidal ideation?</p> <hr/> <p>The prediction model for suicidal ideation centered on CBCL variables has one detrimental disadvantage: low sensitivity. This simple model has a specificity near 1, which means healthy participants without suicidal ideation are almost always appended the “safe” label. On the other hand, the model’s low sensitivity (around 80%) indicates that among participants with suicidal ideation, 1 out of 5 are misunderstood as not having suicidal thoughts and are classified “safe.” If this model is directly utilized in real life, it would not only fail to recognize 400 out of 2000 South Korean adolescents thinking of suicide (as of 2020), but would even misjudge them “safe.”</p> <p>Since the CBCL questionnaire obtained from the ABCD Study® requests caregivers’ opinions on their children’s behavior, it can be inferred that participants producing false negatives, i.e. high-risk individuals misunderstood as not having suicidal thoughts, appear healthy but have internal suffering poorly detected in behavioral traits. Another possibility is the caregiver’s inaccurate assessment of their children’s abnormal behavior, which lies along the lines of previously described survey results about family members being insensitive to pro-suicide signals in adolescents. With mental problems seldom being expressed in South Korean culture, implementing CBCL-centered prediction in South Korea would lead to even lower sensitivity than as shown with ABCD Study® data from the U.S.</p> <p>To avoid the potential problems associated with low sensitivity, our next objective was to seek improvement in our prediction model by exploratively accounting for the interactions between CBCL scores and other variables.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_15_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_15_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_15_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_15_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Prediction results on testing data (525 participants) based on demographic and CBCL variables only. The rows indicate presence or absence of suicidal ideation (SI); the columns indicate prediction results. This model's sensitivity is approximately 80%, meaning that among participants with suicidal ideation, 1 out of 5 (in red) end up in false negatives (misunderstood as "safe"). </div> <hr/> <p>How, and with what data, could we find “silent” teens and young adults thinking about suicide? The poor efficacy of the CBCL scores in detecting suicidal ideation in these individuals stems from the fact that the “silent” high-risk group is not well distinguished from healthy adolescents in terms of behavior. We hypothesized that for these high-risk individuals, an interaction term for relationships between biological signs (represented by PRS or brain imaging data) and behavioral traits (represented by CBCL scores) would assist in further, more accurate classifcation. For instance, certain behavioral characteristics common between “silent” suicide thinkers and the control group might coincide with a particular biological state A in the former and another biological state B in the latter. We attempted to account for this interaction by exploratively appending to our model several product terms between the existing variables.</p> <p>Another practical factor to put into consideration is the cost-effectiveness of the screening model. CBCL questionnaires are convenient to request caregivers to fill out, and they are relatively not time-consuming and inexpensive. On the other hand, genomic or brain imaging analyses would not be as convenient and take up more time and resources. Even if genomic or brain imaging analyses significantly increase suicidal ideation predictability when considered along with CBCL scores, these modalities should be administered only for detailed classification.</p> <p>From the above rationale, the low sensitivity of the CBCL-centered model could be improved by employing PRS and brain imaging data to perform a secondary screening on individuals with no suicidal ideation, i.e. true and false negatives. This method is different from conventional complex screening algorithms that further classify the risk group according to degree of risk, but it is appropriate for suicide prevention where minimizing false negatives is crucial in “tightening the safety net.”</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-1 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-10 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_16_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_16_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_16_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_16_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-1 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> To address low sensitivity issues of the CBCL-centered autoML model, we devised a stepwise, two-phase screening protocol. </div> <p>Consequently, we devised a two-phase suicide risk prediction protocol to find “silent” high-risk teens and young adults. In Phase 1, the CBCL-centered prediction model assesses demographic information and CBCL scores of the general adolescent population. Those who are positive for suicidal ideation can immediately arrange for intervention, and those who are negative go through secondary screening (Phase 2). Phase 2 selects “silent” high-risk adolescents with suicidal intent among those initially classified “safe,” and these individuals can also benefit from intervention.</p> <p>We exploratively added product terms between CBCL scores, PRS, and brain imaging data in the autoML model to determine an adequate predictor for Phase 2. The new prediction models were trained and tested as described previously, but we additionally tested the models for adeptness as a Phase 2 screening algorithm. The dataset for additional testing was derived from individuals classified “safe” by the Phase 1 model;* subsequent processing yielded a total 400 participants (26 with suicidal ideation and 374 without).</p> <p>Below are the efficacy indices of prediction model candidates for Phase 2. When tested with general population data, appending product terms did not produce notable changes in efficacy, and some models were even slightly less effective than the CBCL-centered model. However, additional testing revealed that these models could screen a subgroup of high-risk participants that originally produced false negatives in the CBCL-centered model.</p> <p>*Note: We used this subset only for testing Phase 2 model candidates because the sample size was too small to both train and test models as described previously without potential reliability and overfitting issues. In future studies, these models could be trained and tested in larger datasets to become more effective in screening “silent” suicide thinkers.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-8 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_17_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_17_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_17_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_17_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Efficacy indices of Phase 2 prediction model candidates. "Brain" indicates all brain imaging data (brain morphometry, fMRI, dMRI). All variables were selected by significant solitary predictability in the univariate GLM (p &lt; .01). Columns labeled "Phase 2" show efficacy indices for additional testing. </div> <p>Examining the Phase 2 model candidates that were successful in the additional testing, we discovered that product terms between CBCL and brain imaging variables largely determined the dataset classification. In particular, dMRI data crossed with CBCL scores showed explainability similar to that of CBCL scores alone. This implies that information on white matter connectivity, when associated with behavioral characteristics, could reflect some changes in adolescents with suicidal ideation whose behavior closely resembles those without.</p> <p>Meanwhile, explainability of CBCL and PRS data product terms was relatively nondominant. Does this mean that PRS itself is not effective in predicting suicidal thoughts? Including triple product terms for PRS, brain imaging, and CBCL data improved the specificity of Phase 2 model candidates; thus PRS data could influence the classifying criteria through interactions with other variables. In fact, interactions between PRS and brain imaging data may explain more of the differences in suicide thinkers than when appended separately. We investigated this effect more directly by generating autoML models including either demographic information, PRS, and brain imaging data or the former plus product terms between PRS and brain imaging data. Indeed, appending PRS-brain imaging interactions as independent variables drove major improvements in the AUC or accuracy (proportion of classified data that match their true designations) indices.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_18_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_18_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_18_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_18_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Appending product terms representing PRS-brain imaging interactions improves model performance. </div> <p>In summary of the performances of Phase 2 screening model candidates on additional testing, dMRI data led to discovery of around half of “silent” suicide thinkers, although there was a decline in specificity. However, we could seek improvement in this lowered specificity by including interaction terms regarding PRS, brain morphometry, or fMRI data. PRS and brain imaging data, though with minuscule influences on data classification individually, might have potential in enhancing the accuracy of Phase 2 screening. We selected the best fit Phase 2 models as shown below.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-8 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_19_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_19_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_19_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_19_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Selected models for Phase 2 screening. "Brain" indicates all brain imaging data (brain morphometry, fMRI, dMRI). All variables were selected by significant solitary predictability in the univariate GLM (p &lt; .01). Table below depicts prediction results for each model on additional testing data (400 participants). The rows indicate presence or absence of suicidal ideation (SI); the columns indicate prediction results. </div> <hr/> <p>Given the devastating South Korean adolescent suicide crisis, an effective screening model that predicts suicidal ideation could constitute a more immediate approach to overthrow the steep incline of suicide rates. Here, we propose a two-phase suicide risk prediction model that could serve as a prototype in this approach. An ideal nationwide screening protocol would start with requesting caregivers, guardians, and school teachers to complete CBCL assessments. Then, Phase 1 screening would evaluate suicide risk for the general adolescent population based on that CBCL data as well as demographic information. Subsequently, teens and young adults initially classified not to have suicidal ideation would go through Phase 2 screening, where we would obtain PRS or brain imaging data according to the selected Phase 2 model and include them to discover “silent” suicide thinkers.</p> <p>One of the advantages this tedious but potentially effective approach has is that we can identify and “reach out firsthand” to teens and young adults suffering in silence. In a culture that tends to be indifferent to mental illness, South Korean adolescents required much time and courage even to make that decision to talk to their caregiver, teacher, or the school counselor, or to walk into the clinic and seek help. Our proposed model aids in reducing that burden of extensive, indecisive rumination by discovering high-risk youth by a census and actively “reaching out.” In fact, professionals could possibly engage in visiting sessions in environments more friendly to these individuals, prompting a smooth transition into forming healthy social relationships and learning problem-solving and coping skills along with appropriate pharmacotherapy if needed. This multidimensional therapeutic approach is important because it exceeds beyond the simplistic model of curing, or eliminating, suicidal ideation, which could mislead teens and young adults to view their problems as something embarrassing or something they did wrong. Precise intervention based on a thorough prediction model would minimize this stigma effect especially in South Korea, providing safe grounds for these suffering youth to speak up about their deepest troubles such as anxiety or depression.</p> <p>On a further note, with the consent of providers, the valuable information obtained from these South Korean adolescents may open windows for future research to shed light on the contributing factors and pathophysiology of suicidal ideation. Developing a Korean version of the ABCD Study® would give rise to studies based on this ethnically and culturally unique population, adding to the existing literature on adolescent suicide as well as various dysfunctional behavior including mood disorders, attention deficit, aggression, and many others.</p> <p>Even at this hour, there are thousands of beautiful but fragile young South Koreans, and more adolescents around the world, who all are desperately reaching out, looking for someone to really listen to their voices and help them climb out of their suffering. “Reaching out firsthand” means engaging with them hand in hand, resonating with their troubles, and ultimately making a difference in the world for them, and for all of us, to enjoy our lives that we deserve to live to the fullest.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-8 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20221214_20_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20221214_20_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20221214_20_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20221214_20_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Making a difference. </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="psychology"/><category term="psychiatry"/><category term="suicide"/><category term="machine-learning"/><category term="Korea"/><category term="data-science-in-human-neuroimaging"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A proposal to lower South Korean adolescent suicide rates by CBCL-brain/PRS interaction-based risk prediction and precise intervention]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Let Me Start - My premed musical fever</title><link href="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2022/let-me-start/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let Me Start - My premed musical fever"/><published>2022-03-06T22:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-06T22:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2022/let-me-start</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2022/let-me-start/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20220306_00-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20220306_00-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20220306_00-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20220306_00.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Let Me Start. </div> <p>After the <a href="/blog/2019/let-theatre-bloom/">success</a> of “Les Misérables” in high school, I started to get really immersed in the musical theatre genre. Especially with the COVID-19 pandemic and quarantine going on in South Korea, I was seeking an opportunity to connect with people at Seoul National University who share that passion for music and performance. So it wasn’t strange that I hastily submitted my application for Let Me Start, the one-and-only musical theatre club at SNU!</p> <p>Let Me Start is a bustling club consisting of five teams (director, music coordinator, actor, stage designer, and administrator) and hosts semiannual licensed performances, fully staging a show selected at the start of each semester. The works usually staged are original Korean musicals written for small casts, and club members devote their school breaks to intensive daily workshops on character development, scene-making, and musical numbers. As a member of the music coordinator team, I took part in two such performances: “Airport Baby” in September 2021 as a new member and “Superman with the Moon” in February 2022 as music director.</p> <hr/> <p>“Airport Baby” is the story of Josh Cohen, a young Korean American adopted to a Jewish household in the U.S. when he was two years old. Josh has an unsolved question about self-identity that countinuously haunted his mind throughout his childhood and adolescent years: “Where are my roots? Where did I come from?” Initially to meet his Korean birth mother, Josh returns to South Korea to discover the dark reality of his past, unexpectedly encountering friends also searching for “who they really are” on his way. Borrowing Josh’s monologue near the end, he “lives in the present, finds the past, and now awaits the future.”</p> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20220306_01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20220306_01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20220306_01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20220306_01.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-5 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20220306_02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20220306_02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20220306_02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20220306_02.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-3 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-3 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20220306_03_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20220306_03_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20220306_03_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20220306_03_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-3 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20220306_04_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20220306_04_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20220306_04_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20220306_04_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-3 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Photos from the "Airport Baby" performance on September 19, 2021. </div> <p>“Superman with the Moon” has a rather omnibus-like storyline about five young adults in a hillside low-income neighborhood* in Seoul, South Korea. Although the musical mainly provides a lens into the daily life and comic struggles of these friendly, relatable people, it also lets us dive into their histories and untold secrets. One of the iconic characters in this show is Wuhyeon, a young man with intellectual disability who “believes that he can fly,” just like Superman (as in the title). While this arrangement surprises many, it is suggested later in the show that Wuhyeon’s seemingly childish ambition could have another meaning to it.</p> <p>*Note: “Moon” in the title refers to “Daldongne (달동네; Moon-Town),” a Korean expression that corresponds to “shantytown” or “slum.” During rapid urban development in the late 20th century, such neighborhoods formed in the yet underdeveloped, hilly areas of Seoul with steep alleys between closely built houses. The metaphor is said to come from the idea that the moon is seen clearer and “closer” on the hills.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20220306_05-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20220306_05-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20220306_05-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20220306_05.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20220306_06-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20220306_06-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20220306_06-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20220306_06.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-5 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20220306_07-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20220306_07-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20220306_07-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20220306_07.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-3 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20220306_08_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20220306_08_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20220306_08_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20220306_08_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Photos from the "Superman with the Moon" performance on February 24–25, 2022. </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HxAvuMrg0Lc" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> This vlog is a glimpse of the typical 6-hour daily workshop for our "Superman with the Moon" performance. Club members devote their school breaks to intensive daily workshops on character development, scene-making, and musical numbers. </div> <hr/> <p>Aside from the performances, Let Me Start has a very lively community where I could make many close friends from different majors and backgrounds. There were club gatherings, occasional vlogs and special projects, and even galas (also open to past club members) where we would get together to sing and dance to some of our favorite musicals. However, among all those memories, those I really look back to are of the heartwarming celebrations that we planned for each other.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EPiy0jlSxHQ" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> This is a special project in January 2022 that I organized as music director, featuring club members singing "You Will Be Found" from the Broadway musical "Dear Evan Hansen" to spread togetherness in the midst of COVID-19 quarantine. I translated the lyrics into Korean and directed practice workshops and recording sessions. </div> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20220306_09_v2-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20220306_09_v2-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20220306_09_v2-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20220306_09_v2.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-5 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20220306_10-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20220306_10-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20220306_10-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20220306_10.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> And of course, the surprises and birthday parties... (for others' privacy, I only included pictures of myself) </div> <p>My experience in Let Me Start was not always easygoing, but in the end, I think it all comes down to a memory I often look back on, whenever I find myself in challenging situations in medical school. Thank you, Let Me Start members, for being a part of my “good times.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="musical-theatre"/><category term="musical-performance"/><category term="community"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anecdotes from my time as a music director in Seoul National University's musical theatre club]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cognitive overconfidence from reminiscence of giving advice</title><link href="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2021/overconfidence-reminiscence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cognitive overconfidence from reminiscence of giving advice"/><published>2021-12-23T22:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-23T22:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2021/overconfidence-reminiscence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2021/overconfidence-reminiscence/"><![CDATA[<p>*** This was an individual term project in the “Introduction to Experimental Psychology &amp; Lab.” course in Fall 2021, led by Dr. Jooyong Park (Department of Psychology, Seoul National University). This course is where students practice critiques and academic writing on a number of sample research topics before embarking on their own research projects.</p> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-5 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20211223_00-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20211223_00-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20211223_00-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20211223_00.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Overconfidence in word recall from reminiscence of giving advice. </div> <p>*** Reflecting on my experiences in mentoring or tutoring middle and high school students, I noticed that the sole recalling of those sessions where I felt I was able to provide my mentees some kind of advice (even the less helpful ones) promoted self-esteem. I decided to find out if others had similar reactions, and it turned out that they did!</p> <p>*** The immediate conclusion of this work was rather about overconfidence resulting from an experience of authority. However, in retrospect, I think this could be a good example showing that we can remain resilient despite debilitating stress by reminiscing about “good times” when we were appreciated as a “good (knowledgeable) person.”</p> <hr/> <p>Most problems we face living in a dynamic world have no definite answers. To overcome such problematic situations, people often seek advice from those around them. By doing this, we can summarize the situation, brainstorm a variety of empirical solutions or approaches, and possibly come across an innovative breakthrough. Even if the advice does not prove helpful right away, the person-to-person interactions where the advisor and advisee share their thoughts may reinforce the motivation to face and overcome problems. Especially in an academic setting, people inevitably encounter situations where they must acquire knowledge unprecedented in their lives, leading to a frequent need of advice. Academic advice can be classified into two groups that regard either “academic motivation,” e.g. diligence and task persistence, or “academic ability,” e.g. mnemonic techniques and problem-solving strategies.</p> <p>The existing literature on advice in academic settings centered on motivation. Advice giving on academic motivation, as reported by Eskreis-Winkler et al. (2018) and Eskreis-Winkler et al. (2019), is more beneficial to advice givers than advice takers, enhancing academic performance in the former. As opposed to these findings on motivational advice, academic ability-related advising, which might provide more practical assistance, needs more attention in research. Moreover, prior research on academic advice examined the effects of advising in an environment where at least some stimuli relevant to the advice given were still existent. For instance, Eskreis-Winkler et al. (2019) collected report card grades of motivational advice givers at the end of the same semester they gave advice in. In the long term, recalling memories of advice giving might influence task performance differently if the advice givers were consistently required in their everyday lives to exercise knowledge and skills irrelevant to what they advised in the past. Considering these aspects, it would be intriguing to investigate whether memories of giving advice regarding academic ability could potentially be retained completely.</p> <p>Anecdotes of advice giving can be recalled not in its entirety but rather in terms of confidence and motivation. According to Eskreis-Winkler et al. (2018), giving advice raises confidence; however, excessive confidence may incorporate with memories of success, affecting task performance negatively (de Lucia, 2015; Forsyth et al., 2007). Since recalling experiences of advice giving was reported to increase perceived influence and sense of power (Schaerer et al., 2018), memories of advising could over-induce confidence as by looking back to successful moments in the past. It is questionable that reminiscence of giving advice on academic ability contributes solely to maintaining academic skills initially enhanced with advice giving, without reinforcing self-confidence.</p> <p>To complement the above shortcomings in academic advice research, we asked whether reminiscence of giving advice induces overconfidence. Specifically, we evaluated the effects of recalling anecdotes of advising mnemonic techniques on over-prediction of future memory task performance. Participants were assigned to either the control or the experimental group, and each group completed a memory task after recalling vacation memories or experiences of giving advice on memorization, respectively. At completion of the memory task, we questioned the participants about their predictions on the number of correct answers they would provide if they were to undergo another similar task in the near future. Giving advice would reinforce the belief that one is an “influential person” and be remembered like successful moments. In other words, the fact that one “gave advice” would have left a greater impression than the exact mnemonic techniques they advised about. Therefore, we expected that although the experimental group’s mnemonic techniques or skills were not to noticeably improve after the recalling session, this group would over-predict future task performance based on self-confidence only. With this rationale, we hypothesized that reminiscence of giving advice leads to overconfidence in task performance.</p> <hr/> <p>Method</p> <p>Prior to the experimental procedure, we employed G*Power to calculate the adequate sample size for the experimental design (Faul et al., 2007). At least 126 participants were required to yield a Cohen’s d of 0.5 with 80% power (two-tailed, alpha = .05).</p> <p>Participants: We recruited 54 college students in their twenties. The average age for the participants was 21.0 (SD = 1.64), and there were 17 males and 37 females.</p> <p>Tasks and Stimuli: Participants initially underwent a recall task to let the experimental group reminisce of advice giving. Akin to de Lucia (2015) and Schaerer et al. (2018), participants were instructed to freely think of memories relevant to an assigned topic and write a description of those memories. The recall topics for control and experimental groups were “memories from a vacation” and “memories of giving advice on memorization,” respectively.</p> <p>To assess the overconfidence from recalling memories of giving advice, participants were assigned a cognitive task where they memorize foreign language vocabulary. We randomly selected 50 words from core entries in the Abenaki-English dictionary from Day (1994). The Abenaki language is an endangered language, minimizing the effect of the participants’ prior knowledge of foreign languages. The meaning of each word was provided as Korean translations of the corresponding English entries in Day (1994). The task comprised of a “learning phase” and a “testing phase.” In the learning phase, participants memorized the 50 Abenaki-Korean word pairs for five minutes without writing them down. In the testing phase, 25 among the 50 pairs were randomly selected, and participants were given only the Korean meaning in each pair. Then, the participants were given 2.5 minutes to answer the corresponding Abenaki word for each Korean meaning entry.</p> <p>Assessment Tools: We evaluated the vividity of memories that the participants accessed in the recall task by employing a five-point scale question akin to de Lucia (2015). Participants indicated the item closest to how vivid their memories were, among “could not envision anything (0 points)” to “vivid as if just before my eyes (4 points).” For the experimental group, we inquired how influential the advice given was in the participants’ memories. Subjective influence was assessed by two seven-point scale questions akin to Schaerer et al. (2018). Participants indicated the item closest to the extent they agreed to the following questions, among “strongly disagree (0 points)” to “strongly agree (6 points)”: “Would the advice taker have carefully listened to your advice?” and “Would the advice taker have put your advice to action?”</p> <p>We examined participants’ predictions of their performance on a prospective similar task to assess overconfidence in the cognitive task on foreign language vocabulary memorization. Following Fischer &amp; Oppenheimer (2021), we instructed participants to provide the predicted number of correct answers if they were to be tested after a similar learning experience. We additionally evaluated self-confidence and performance prediction for the current task. For self-confidence, we employed a five-point scale question akin to de Lucia (2015) immediately before the cognitive task. Participants indicated the item closest to the extent they felt confident in the following learning and testing sessions, among “strongly unconfident (0 points)” to “strongly confident (4 points).” Performance prediction for the current task was assessed by collecting the predicted number of correct answers for the testing session before and after the cognitive task.</p> <p>Procedure: The experiment took place individually in a remote setting, and participants were randomly assigned to the control or experimental group. We provided all participants with a written description of the experimental procedure. Following the introduction of the study as an investigation of vocabulary learning in a controlled environment, the experimental group was asked if they had prior experience of giving advice on memorization. This question was to select only the participants who had advice-giving experience that they could recall in the subsequent procedure, excluding data from those who did not have such experience. The participants then underwent the recall task for five minutes, during which we explained that a customized vocabulary learning task would be developed based on information given in the prior steps. Immediately after the recall task, participants answered one question about the vividity of recall. The experimental group answered two more questions about the subjective influence of their advice. After this step, participants reported their self-confidence and predicted their performance for the following cognitive task, one question for each. The cognitive task totaled 7.5 minutes in duration: five minutes of learning phase and 2.5 minutes of testing phase. At completion of the cognitive task, participants predicted their performance for the testing phase as well as their future performance on a similar task to measure overconfidence, one question for each.</p> <p>Statistics: We employed Student’s t-test to confirm that reminiscence of giving advice leads to overconfidence. Before analysis, we excluded seven participants who reported not having prior experience of academic advice and three participants who did not follow the experimental procedure adequately.</p> <hr/> <p>Results</p> <p>To examine the effect of recalling experience of giving advice on overconfidence, Student’s t-test was applied to the number of correct answers in the testing session along with the participants’ predictions on future performance on a similar task. There was no significant difference between the control and experimental group in the number of correct answers in the testing session. However, the predicted number of correct answers in a prospective similar test was significantly higher in the experimental group (t(42) = 2.19, p = .018, d = 0.66). Meanwhile, the experimental group had a significant difference between the number of correct answers in the testing session and future performance prediction, which was non-existent in the control group (t(21) = 2.97, p = .004, d = 0.63). The finding that the experimental group over-predicts future task performance implies that reminiscence of giving advice induces overconfidence.</p> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-5 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20211223_01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20211223_01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20211223_01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20211223_01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-6 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20211223_02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20211223_02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20211223_02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20211223_02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> (up) Number of correct answers in the testing phase of the current cognitive task (Current Task) and predictions on future performance on a similar task (Future Prediction). Participants were instructed to answer in integers between 0 and 25 (total number of word pairs given). The superscripts indicate statistical significance at p &lt; .05 in the corresponding entries. Outliers are included, but excluding them does not alter significance. (down) Boxplot of the above data. * and ** indicate statistical significance at p &lt; .05 and p &lt; .01, respectively. </div> <p>Student’s t-test was applied to the participants’ self-confidence and performance prediction for the current task to explore the factors contributing to overconfidence shown above. The experimental group exhibited significantly high levels of self-confidence and prior prediction of the number of correct answers in the testing session, compared to the control group (t(42) = 3.47, p &lt; .001, d = 0.56; t(42) = 3.13, p = .002, d = 0.96). On the contrary, the post-testing prediction of the number of correct answers did not differ between experimental conditions and did not significantly differ from the actual number of correct answers in each group. The above results demonstrate that the experimental group, having recalled experience of giving advice, positively predicted their performance on the imminent cognitive task with high self-confidence. Post-testing performance evaluation of the already completed task, however, is less likely to exhibit such positive prediction.</p> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-7 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20211223_03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20211223_03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20211223_03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20211223_03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Self-confidence index and performance predictions of the participants regarding the current cognitive task. Self-confidence was measured prior to the task (Pre-testing Self-confidence). Participants were instructed to answer in a five-point scale (0–4 points) as listed in the method section. Higher scores mean higher self-confidence. Performance predictions were assessed as expected number of correct answers either before and after the task (respectively Pre-testing and Post-testing Prediction). Participants were instructed to answer in integers between 0 and 25 (total number of word pairs given). The superscripts indicate statistical significance at p &lt; .05 in the corresponding entries. Outliers are included, but excluding them does not alter significance. </div> <p>We employed correlation analyses between the experimental group’s predictions on future performance and either the vividity of recall or subjective influence of advice giving. We expected that this would aid in further characterizing the relationship between the experimental group’s recall task and their overconfidence. Indeed, the vividity of recall and subjective influence of advice giving both were significantly correlated with the experimental group’s predicted number of correct answers in a prospective similar test (r(20) = .57, p = .006; r(20) = .63, p = .002). In the control group, such a relationship did not exist between vividity of recall and future performance prediction. This implies that higher overconfidence occurs when the memories of giving advice are more vivid or when one feels that their advice was more influential to the advice taker.</p> <p>The experimental group’s vividity of recall and subjective influence of advice giving were not significantly correlated with the actual number of correct answers in the cognitive task. There were no significant differences between experimental conditions in vividity of recall. These results imply that there is a minimal possibility of factors irrelevant to the recall topic in the recall task design acting as confounding variables in the following procedure.</p> <hr/> <p>Discussion</p> <p>This study aimed to investigate whether reminiscence of giving advice induces overconfidence by comparing with the control group the performance predictions of the experimental group, who recalled advice-giving experiences on memorization, on a prospective task. The experimental group’s numbers of correct answers in the assigned cognitive task were not significantly different from the control group; however, the experimental group anticipated higher scores if they were to undergo another similar task in the near future. The excessive self-confidence on future task performance expressed in the experimental group, exceeding their capabilities demonstrated in the assigned task, supports our hypothesis that reminiscence of giving advice leads to overconfidence.</p> <p>In follow-up analyses of the overconfident experimental group, these participants were more self-confident about and predicted better performance in the imminent cognitive task. This increased self-confidence and self-assurance may have been conveyed into over-prediction of future performance. Thus, recalling experiences of giving advice would have provoked overconfidence in the participants’ perception of the assigned cognitive task, resulting in overevaluation of future performance even after the assigned task. It is notable that both experimental groups provided less correct answers in the testing session than they anticipated prior to the cognitive task. Participants in both groups acknowledged their poor-than-expected results, as shown in the post-testing prediction of the number of correct answers. Since the experimental group over-predicted future performance despite their acknowledgement of subpar scores in the assigned task, we confirmed that the overconfidence from advice-giving experience is retained in a robust manner.</p> <p>Moreover, correlation analyses demonstrated stronger overconfidence in the experimental group when the advice-giving memories accessed in the recall task were more vivid. Considering that vividity of recall had no significant correlation with actual scores in the testing session, it is suggested that the experimental group reminisced their advice-giving experience with a focus on self-assurance rather than the contents of the anecdotes themselves. Higher overconfidence also occurred in participants who reported that their advice would have proved more influential to the advice taker. We can infer from these findings that sole experiences of giving advice, like successful memories, strengthen the belief that one is an “influential person” and imprint major positive impressions on one’s sense of self-assurance.</p> <p>The above analysis results converge on the implication that giving advice on academic ability is remembered as an opportunity for enhanced subjective influence and less about the knowledge conveyed through advising, leading to overconfidence in the long term. People are commonly requested to give academic advice because of their outstanding academic ability or clever studying strategies. Even in instances where this is not the case, giving advice improves self-esteem via the perception that the advice giver “knows more information than” the advice taker and is also beneficial in establishing positive self-identity, i.e. “a person skilled in aspects relevant to the advice given.” As the advice-giving anecdote moves farther into the past, one’s relevant academic ability may not be further developed due to lack of personal effort or environmental cues; therefore, one may have difficulties in remembering the strategies they exercised on future occasions. However, the memory of advice giving itself is consistently retained as a supportive rationale of the past self, a person “more knowledgeable and more skilled than others.” This overevaluation of the past self as an influential person who was asked to give advice may be what resulted in self-confidence and self-assurance exceeding current capabilities. This overconfidence, as this study suggests, could be maintained moving forward without encountering a drastic failure.</p> <p>The effect of reminiscence of giving advice on overconfidence described in this study is in line with existing literature asserting that memories of success, along with excessive self-confidence, impedes task performance (de Lucia, 2015; Forsyth et al., 2007). The implications that advice-giving experience imprints in self-concept based on subjective influence support research findings on the increase of perceived influence and sense of power (Schaerer et al., 2018). Different from advice related to academic motivation, which could be easily kept as a desirable habit, people giving advice regarding academic ability should exercise relevant skills to further enhance and maintain it. This suggests that further clarifications are required to expand prior conclusions on motivational advice and self-confidence, in Eskreis-Winkler et al. (2018) and Eskreis-Winkler et al. (2019), to include academic ability-related advice. Additional strategies other than cooperating by exchanging advice may assist in consistent improvement and practice of academic ability. Here, we propose the possibility of long-term overconfidence provocation by giving advice with possible contributing factors. These findings are favorable of plausible shortcomings in learning methods that involve advice giving.</p> <p>More comprehensive research including various skill domains will aid in generalizing the above discussion, considering that the two experimental groups and mnemonic technique assessment incorporated in the study design may limit our scope of observed effect. Further studies should focus on advice regarding critical thinking or problem-solving skills, both more complex than memorization, and even academic motivation. Prospective comparisons could also evaluate experimental groups who gave advice instead of recalling advice-giving, who recalled experience of receiving advice, or who received advice. Among the variables, post-testing performance predictions immediately followed the test session, allowing participants to infer the number of correct answers in the memory task without much effort. A longitudinal study would measure perceived task performance after a period as well as control for the time elapsed between advice giving and recalling that occasion. Furthermore, practical findings on the memory and recall circuits of advice-giving experience will lead to effective learning models based on advice giving and a more extensive understanding of advice-giving behavior itself.</p> <p>Human life exists as an inevitable constituent of society and environment, and there is no identical problem in such dynamic settings with a myriad of variables. In this sense, exchanging advice when facing challenges could be seen as a fit behavioral trait to draw the most rational conclusions grounded by empirical solutions from many. However, even if one collects so many opinions from others, it is that person themselves that establishes desirable strategies, overcomes challenging problems, and grows to be a better person. If one possesses exceptional assets worth advising others to develop, one should not reside in influencing others, putting personal effort in constantly refining those skills. We hope more specific research on the long-term effects of advice giving and its contribution to overconfidence to maximize academic motivation and ability enhancement through advice.</p> <hr/> <p>References</p> <p>Day, G. M. (1994). Western Abenaki dictionary: Volume 1: Abenaki-English. Ottawa: University of Ottawa Press.</p> <p>de Lucia, L. (2015). Priming memories: Effects on motivation and confidence. The Huron University College Journal of Learning and Motivation, 53(1), 34–83.</p> <p>Eskreis-Winkler, L., Fishbach, A., &amp; Duckworth, A. L. (2018). Dear Abby: Should I give advice or receive it?. Psychological Science, 29(11), 1797–1806.</p> <p>Eskreis-Winkler, L., Milkman, K. L., Gromet, D. M., &amp; Duckworth, A. L. (2019). A large-scale field experiment shows giving advice improves academic outcomes for the advisor. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 116(30), 14808–14810.</p> <p>Faul, F., Erdfelder, E., Lang, A.-G., &amp; Buchner, A. (2007). G*Power 3: A flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behavior Research Methods, 39(2), 175–191.</p> <p>Fischer, M., &amp; Oppenheimer, D. (2021). Harder than you think: How outside resistance leads to overconfidence. Psychological Science, 32(4), 598–610.</p> <p>Forsyth, D. R., Lawrence, N. K., Burnette, J. L., &amp; Baumeister, R. F. (2007). Attempting to improve the academic performance of struggling college students by bolstering their self-esteem: An intervention that backfired. Journal of Social and Clinical Psychology, 26(4), 447–459.</p> <p>Schaerer, M., Tost, L. P., Huang, L., Gino, F., &amp; Larrick, R. (2018). Advice giving: A subtle pathway to power. Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin, 44(5), 746–761.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="psychology"/><category term="overconfidence"/><category term="memory-task"/><category term="priming"/><category term="giving-advice"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The influence of empowering memories on anticipation of word recall task performance]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Korean concept of patient-centered medicine and healing： In comparison with Jacques Lacan’s “sinthome”-based psychoanalytic examination</title><link href="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2020/Lacanian-healing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Korean concept of patient-centered medicine and healing： In comparison with Jacques Lacan’s “sinthome”-based psychoanalytic examination"/><published>2020-07-12T23:50:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-12T23:50:00+00:00</updated><id>https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2020/Lacanian-healing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2020/Lacanian-healing/"><![CDATA[<p>*** This was an individual term project in the “French Reading &amp; Writing Ⅱ” course in Spring 2020 at <a href="https://english.minjok.hs.kr/">Korean Minjok Leadership Academy</a>, supervised by the French teacher. This course, taken in the spring semester of the senior year (twelfth grade), is designed for advanced French learners at CEFR B1–B2 level. Alongside reading and discussing “Le Petit Prince” by Antoine de Saint-Exupery and “L’étranger” by Albert Camus, this individual term project encouraged students (like me) to choose an originally French text and indulge in thoroughly understanding the material in its original entirety to incorporate it in a research topic of choice.</p> <div class="row justify-content-sm-center mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-5 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20200712_00-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20200712_00-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20200712_00-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20200712_00.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The Korean concept of patient-centered medicine and healing: In comparison with Jacques Lacan’s “sinthome”-based psychoanalytic examination. </div> <p>*** As for now, only the abstract is available in English; the main article will be modified and added eventually, ensuring adequate translation and cross-checking with existing psychoanalysis research (now that I am a medical student interested in psychiatry).</p> <hr/> <p>Abstract</p> <p>Patient-centered care has become the crux of doctor-patient relationships nowadays. Various medical institutions worldwide are developing patient-centered processes in virtue of promoting internal healing from the patient’s ultimate medical experience. However, there are problems in incorporating patient-centered care into existing medical systems, especially regarding psychiatric discourses. Korea is not an exception, only that communication is made further difficult by the characteristic social, cultural, and linguistic backgrounds of Korean patients.</p> <p>To introduce a new perspective into Korean psychiatric patient-centered care, Jacques Lacan’s psychoanalytic examination methods were to be compared with the fundamental processes of patient-centered psychiatric discourse. Here, we thoroughly reviewed “Présentation de Gérard Lucas,” a record of one of Lacan’s public discourses, focusing on subtle nuances of the French language. Analyzing the process of this discourse, the recognition and acceptance of “sinthome,” a Lacanian concept for symptoms that are to prevent ego death, were found analogous to the essential values of “healing” pursued during patient-centered psychiatric therapy. Linguistically symbolized psychiatric advice, from perspectives similar to the acceptance of sinthome, may provide new insights for culturally sensitive patient-centered discourse in Korean psychiatric therapy.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="psychology"/><category term="psychiatry"/><category term="healing"/><category term="psychoanalysis"/><category term="Korea"/><category term="culturally-sensitive"/><category term="French"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An original French text research project on a record of Lacan’s public psychiatric discourse]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Let Theatre Bloom： Les Misérables in Hoengseong</title><link href="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2019/let-theatre-bloom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let Theatre Bloom： Les Misérables in Hoengseong"/><published>2019-10-30T18:50:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-30T18:50:00+00:00</updated><id>https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2019/let-theatre-bloom</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://willijeong1.github.io/blog/2019/let-theatre-bloom/"><![CDATA[<div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/20191030_00-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/20191030_00-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/20191030_00-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/20191030_00.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Let Theatre Bloom: Les Misérables in Hoengseong. </div> <p>Putting together a full-blown musical performance was a challenge that appeared close to impossible for members of THE SCENE, a musical theatre club founded in 2018 at <a href="https://english.minjok.hs.kr/">Korean Minjok Leadership Academy</a> (including me). We had almost no prior experience in actually staging shows before, let alone one of the world’s finest masterpieces!</p> <p>Setting on this overwhelming objective in the start of Spring 2019, we had so many worries about what could go wrong (who wouldn’t?). However, as we spent tons and tons of our precious lunch and after-school hours steadily practicing and refining our performance, those worries eventually turned into hope. We even started to see ourselves in the characters; striving to live and love amidst frustrating, “miserable” conditions.</p> <p>Continuing with our preparations for the show scheduled in late October, our growing interest towards “Les Misérables” prompted us to look across genres to the original novel written by Victor Hugo. Five passionate members of the musical club, including me, organized a semester-long course using the school’s newly implemented “Integrated Project” curriculum, where we thoroughly went through the entire novel with French, European History, and English Literature teachers to truly understand the cultural and historical implications behind each scene of this massive work of pure brilliance. Although this again was a major endeavor, we discovered so many magnificent scenes and descriptions not well depicted in the musical that taught us closely about the ups and downs of human life, and the strong bond of love that transcends that turmoil.</p> <p>Deeply inspired by the novel, we felt the need to convey its valuable messages across the language barrier to the people coming to see our show. We ourselves translated all of the subtitles for the musical performance into Korean, taking into account the narratives and character development rather simplified in the show as well as culturally specific connotations in the original French text. You can see the outcome in the subtitles of the following videos!</p> <p>Listed below are the full videos of our two-hour-long performance. In terms of the actual performance, I was music coordinator and also played Enjolras with the red and gold jacket.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N6g92Rsh0hM" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6kPDCYec7_E" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm-2 mt-3 mt-md-0"> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> (left) Act 1. (right) Act 2. </div> <p>I would like to express my deepest gratitude to all THE SCENE members, especially the four brilliant friends without whom the journey through the novel would have been merely unthinkable.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="musical-theatre"/><category term="KMLA"/><category term="musical-performance"/><category term="community"/><category term="high-school-stuff"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A high school performance of the renowned "Les Misérables" for the school community and locals]]></summary></entry></feed>